# MATTHEW MARTIN

Herndon, VA 20171 ♦ 571-247-6010 ♦ matthewdeanmartin@gmail.com https://github.com/matthewdeanmartin

I'm an experienced and effective technical lead. See long resume for full details of 24 years of experience.

I wrote python on a daily basis at Artemis Consulting and Burson Marsteller. This included writing the app, packaging it, deploying it and reviewing the python of other developers on my team.

UIPath & RPA. I participated in a proof of concept pilot at USPTO. While my participation was superficial, at other jobs I have automated Microsoft Office and browsers using far less userfriendly techniques. I have used screen scraping techniques at various times to deal with applications that have no API. I also used playwright for end-to-end testing.

I wrote some machine learning models at Burson Marsteller using scikit-learn for doing social media analytics. I was maitenance developer for a variety of other machine learning models that I didn't create, but needed to work with the supporting code. This also involved doing maintenance development to keep the models running as the remote APIs evolved.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Tech Lead (Supervisor), Artemis Consulting, 2019-2024

- Support contract for US Copyright Office
- Led technical team to deliver the Public Record copyright search engine to production, starting from a greenfield application.
- Supervisor for 3-5 subordinates, mostly software developers. Conducted technical interviews, wrote tickets, set quality standards, filled skill gaps, retained core dev team for five years.
- Wrote *significant* amounts of code in Python, TypeScript, Gitlab build scripts, Terraform code in all areas of the application.
- Maintained good relationships with client. Participated and complied with all areas of Scrum and SAFe software methodology.

## Systems Architect, ASRC, 2019-2019

- Support contract for USPTO
- Participate in various proof of concepts for docker, kiosks, RPA, Azure Chatbots.

## Software Developer (Supervisor), Burson Marsteller, 2016-2019

- Supervisor for 2-5 software developers.
- Maintenance development on legacy marketing and public relations analytics apps.

## Senior Software Engineer, Forsmarsh, 2014-2016

• Support contracts for NIST and Veteran's Administration, .NET and Python

## Software Developer, CACI, 2012-2014

- Support contract for Department of Defense at the Pentagon
- Maintenance developer for a Javascript, Telerik and ASP.NET hybrid front end.

## Senior Consultant, Procentrix 2008-2012

- Support contract for TSA
- Maintenance developer for a ASP.NET and SQL Server application

## DBA/Software Developer III, DRC, 2005-2008

- Support contracts for USAF and NARA
- SQL Server DBA tasks as well as application development tasks in C#, asp, ASP.NET

## Systems Developer I, Prince William County, 1998-2005

MATTHEW MARTIN Page 2

## **SKILLS**

- Excellent: Python, C#, TypeScript, Javascript. Good enough: Java. Legacy: VB6, VBA, VB.NET. Willing and eager to learn: Rust, Go, PHP, Ruby
- Ops: SQL Server, Postgres, REDIS, Opensearch, Bash, Terraform, Docker
- Cloud: AWS EC2, ECS, ECR, RDS, API Gateway, ALB, DynamoDB, SQS
- More keywords in long resume. Willing and eager to learn more about Azure.

## **EDUCATION**

Masters of Economics, University of Akron, Ohio, 1996-1998 BSBA Finance, University of Akron, Ohio, 1990-1996